{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "AWS Elastic Beanstalk is a service that manages web infrastructure.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which AWS service reduces network latency?",
      "options": ["Elastic Load Balancing", "AWS Transit Gateway", "AWS Direct Connect", "Amazon CloudFront"],
      "correct_answer": "Amazon CloudFront"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of database is AWS DynamoDB?",
      "options": ["NoSQL database", "Relational database", "Document database"],
      "correct_answer": "NoSQL database"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is AWS EC2?",
      "options": [
        "AWS EC2 is a virtual server in the AWS Cloud",
        "AWS EC2 is a data center",
        "AWS EC2 is a resource monitoring service",
        "AWS EC2 is a serverless compute service"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "AWS EC2 is a virtual server in the AWS Cloud"
    },
    {
      "question": "AWS Regions is part of the AWS Global Infrastructure.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Amazon S3 storage class has the lowest cost?",
      "options": ["S3 Standard", "S3 Intelligent-Tiering", "S3 Glacier Deep Archive"],
      "correct_answer": "S3 Glacier Deep Archive"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is AWS EFS?",
      "options": ["AWS Efficient File System", "AWS Enterprise File System", "AWS Elastic File System"],
      "correct_answer": "AWS Elastic File System"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are Edge Locations?",
      "options": [
        "Data centers that store petabytes of data",
        "Physical hard drives",
        "AWS Regions",
        "Data centers that deliver data fast to the users"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Data centers that deliver data fast to the users"
    },
    {
      "question": "Denial-of-Service (DoS) attack comes from different sources.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of AWS Organizations service?",
      "options": [
        "AWS Organizations helps you manage multiple AWS Accounts",
        "AWS Organizations optimizes your system performance",
        "AWS Organizations organizes your services and makes service usage reports",
        "AWS Organizations groups your applications and manages them"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "AWS Organizations helps you manage multiple AWS Accounts"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an AWS Migration Strategy?",
      "options": ["Replatforming", "Governance", "Auditability"],
      "correct_answer": "Replatforming"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which perspective of the AWS Cloud Adoption Framework focuses on minimizing the business risks?",
      "options": ["Business Perspective", "People Perspective", "Operations Perspective", "Governance Perspective"],
      "correct_answer": "Governance Perspective"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which pillar of the AWS Well-Architected Framework focuses on recovering from service or infrastructure disruptions?",
      "options": ["Reliability", "Performance Efficiency", "Operational Excellence"],
      "correct_answer": "Reliability"
    },
    {
      "question": "Economies of scale continually reduce AWS Cloud pricing.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which service sends and receives messages between application components?",
      "options": ["AWS Lambda", "AWS Snowmobile", "AWS CloudTrail", "AWS Simple Queue Service (AWS SQS)"],
      "correct_answer": "AWS Simple Queue Service (AWS SQS)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is responsible for managing storage and database in AWS Cloud?",
      "options": ["Customers", "AWS"],
      "correct_answer": "AWS"
    },
    {
      "question": "AWS Artifact is a service that provides access to AWS security and compliance reports.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which AWS service helps you create users and provide them security access?",
      "options": ["AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM)", "AWS Redshift", "AWS Direct Connect", "AWS CloudFormation"],
      "correct_answer": "AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which AWS service helps you build text chatbots?",
      "options": ["Amazon Lex", "Amazon Polly", "Amazon Comprehend", "Amazon Transcribe"],
      "correct_answer": "Amazon Lex"
    },
    {
      "question": "Can all accounts of an AWS Organization be billed with a single bill?",
      "options": ["Yes", "No"],
      "correct_answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which database is ideal for large organizations and enterprises?",
      "options": ["Amazon Aurora", "MySQL", "PostgreSQL"],
      "correct_answer": "Amazon Aurora"
    },
    {
      "question": "If an instance store reboots, does the data in the instance persist?",
      "options": ["Yes", "No"],
      "correct_answer": "No"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which sentence best describes AWS CloudWatch?",
      "options": [
        "CloudWatch monitors your account and recommends you cost optimization and performance improvement actions.",
        "CloudWatch is a monitoring service that monitors your resources, and configures automatic alarms.",
	"CloudWatch is a service tha logs your AWS environment Actions. It is used to create events that describe how your application is being used."
      ],
      "correct_answer": "CloudWatch is a monitoring service that monitors your resources, and configures automatic alarms."
    },
    {
      "question": "What does AWS Shield protect from?",
      "options": ["Dos and DDoS attacks", "Software vulnerabilities", "Infrastructure threats"],
      "correct_answer": "Dos and DDoS attacks"
    },
    {
      "question": "Based on application's network requests, AWS Web Application Firewall can block network traffic.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which AWS service manages encryption and decryption of data?",
      "options": ["AWS Key Management Service (AWS KMS)", "AWS WAF", "AWS GuardDuty", "AWS Inspector"],
      "correct_answer": "AWS Key Management Service (AWS KMS)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is true about AWS S3?",
      "options": ["It is a data lake service", "It is a distributed storage service", "It is a secure cloud-based storage service"],
      "correct_answer": "It is a secure cloud-based storage service"
    },
{
      "question": "AWS Elastic Block Store Snapshot is:",
      "options": ["Incremental data backup", "Differential data backup", "Full data backup"],
      "correct_answer": "Incremental data backup"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which AWS storage service is designed to transfer petabytes of data in and out of the cloud?",
      "options": ["AWS Snowmobile", "AWS Redshift", "AWS S3"],
      "correct_answer": "AWS Snowmobile"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which tool lets you visualize and manage your AWS costs?",
      "options": ["AWS Price Calculator", "AWS Cost Explorer", "AWS Budgets"],
      "correct_answer": "AWS Cost Explorer"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an IAM Policy?",
      "options": [
        "IAM Policy is a document that customizes user permissions for AWS services and resources",
        "IAM Policy is an entity that interacts with AWS resources or services",
        "IAM Policy is a temporary access to AWS services or resources"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "IAM Policy is a document that customizes user permissions for AWS services and resources"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is called a service that lets you run code without needing to think about servers?",
      "options": ["AWS Serverless", "AWS Lambda", "AWS ECS", "AWS EC2 Auto Scaling"],
      "correct_answer": "AWS Lambda"
    },
    {
      "question": "DNS stands for 'Data Name System'.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is responsible for managing platform and customer data in the AWS Cloud?",
      "options": ["Customers", "AWS"],
      "correct_answer": "Customers"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which AWS database service provided historical data of your application changes?",
      "options": ["AWS Quantum Ledger Database", "AWS Neptune", "AWS ElastiCache", "AWS DocumentDB"],
      "correct_answer": "AWS Quantum Ledger Database"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is AWS DynamoDB Accelerator capable of?",
      "options": [
        "Improves read times of non-relational data",
        "Improves write times of documents",
        "Improves read times of relational data",
        "Improves visualization times of graphs"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Improves read times of non-relational data"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which AWS service do you need to use to get complete history of user activity?",
      "options": ["AWS CloudWatch", "AWS TrustedAdvisor", "AWS CloudTrail"],
      "correct_answer": "AWS CloudTrail"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does AWS Marketplace allow you to do?",
      "options": [
        "AWS Marketplace lets you see the cost analysis of all AWS Cloud Services",
        "AWS Marketplace lets you list all AWS Cloud Services",
        "AWS Marketplace lets you list and sell software"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "AWS Marketplace lets you list and sell software"
    },
    {
      "question": "Containers are an essential concept in microservice architectures.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "With AWS EC2 you only pay for the compute time that you use.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which service helps you reduce development time and complexity of Machine Learning (ML)?",
      "options": ["AWS SageMaker", "AWS Redshift", "AWS Lex", "AWS Elastic Beanstalk"],
      "correct_answer": "AWS SageMaker"
    }
  ]
}

